<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>A link collection by Net-Enjoyers</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on A link collection by Net-Enjoyers</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://net-enjoyers.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Link collection: 12</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/12/</guid><description>Antoni You Need A Budget I deal with the spending problem for quite some time. But it is not necessarily an overspending one, actually, I spend less than I earn and manage to save money for bigger buys and investments. My problem is mostly connected with emotions, especially guilt when I feel like I am spending too much on daily basis but at the end of the month, everything is fine.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 11</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/11/</guid><description>Antoni You&amp;rsquo;re welcome Very interesting situation has happened to me today. I had a big problem with passing one of the lessons in Duolingo Chinese course. Lesson was about magic words 谢谢 (thank you) and 对不起 (I&amp;rsquo;m sorry).
What took me by surprise was the struggle that I had with the responses to those magic words.
When someone says &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry&amp;rdquo; you respond with 没关系 (no problem). When someone says &amp;ldquo;Thank you&amp;rdquo; you respond with 不客气 (you&amp;rsquo;re welcome) I literally tried to pass the lesson like 5 or 6 times and every time I failed on the phrase &amp;ldquo;No problem&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 10</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/10/</guid><description>Mateusz Where Does Bad Code Come From? I never had a real in person mentor that I would take from piles of knowledge and in times of trouble I&amp;rsquo;d think to myself &amp;ldquo;How would he approach this problem?&amp;rdquo;. Casey Muratori has been to me - code-wise at least - the closest thing to a mentor I ever had. Being curious about the world view someone has on a given subject shows that you respect that person.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 9</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/09/</guid><description>Mateusz Backblaze B2 For a long time now I knew that I&amp;rsquo;m asking for trouble storing all the files that I care about on my main and only hard drive. If it breaks all my files that are close to me are just gone. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of a weird trick that the mind is playing on you. You do not need all those files, they are not crucial, your life does not depend on them.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 8</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/08/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/08/</guid><description>Mateusz Down the ergonomic keyboard rabbit hole Realizing that working on a computer will destroy your body if you do not take care of it is the better the sooner it comes. Buying equipment that will aid in your work is money not spent but invested. If you will have to stop working in the field you know most about because you can&amp;rsquo;t physically do it is money lost. Money is not you and your work is not you.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 7 (Switch around)</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/07/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/07/</guid><description>Special post This post we decide to experiment with an idea. We would come up with something that diverges from the beaten path and see how it turns out. The first idea that Antoni came up with is switching our posts around. In short: I choose two blog posts and send them to Antoni and he writes about them and the other way around.
Mateusz It&amp;rsquo;s Later Than You Think The realization that life is brisk is sudden and crushing.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 6</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/06/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/06/</guid><description>Antoni being old soul I heard about the term &amp;ldquo;old soul&amp;rdquo; few months ago during conversation with a guy from America. After exchange of thoughts and life experiences he told me that they have a name for my point of view in the US, I am na &amp;ldquo;old soul&amp;rdquo;, I feel older than I am. This conversation was very eye-opening for me and stays in my mind to this day. When checking Refind I found article with this term in the title and it quickly caught my attention.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 5</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/05/</guid><description>Mateusz Quite OK Image Format I think we all accepted the current state of affairs when it comes to cutting edge. Things that are advanced and high-tech are by nature required to be complex beyond our comprehension. Have you ever step into a core C++ function or a class while debugging? Or maybe you tried to read a specification about some format to implement it and learn how it works. If so you experienced the sheer terror that awakes when stuff like GLIBC source code is on your screen.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 4</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/04/</guid><description>Mateusz BOOKSTORES: How to Read More Books in the Golden Age of Content Living in the &amp;ldquo;golden age of content&amp;rdquo; has many benefits. You can basically watch anything, anywhere, anytime. Servers do not sleep, phones are slim and the extension of your arms and companies want to have the most diverse content catalogue. Information is all around us, yet I&amp;rsquo;d argue that sadly we are slipping into medieval fairy tails and folklore rather than grounded knowledge and scientifically proven facts.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 3</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/03/</guid><description>Mateusz Wide-band WebSDR Electromagnetic radiation is a spectrum so incredibly attached to today&amp;rsquo;s humans it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine life without it. From radio, WiFi, Bluetooth, 4G/5G, TV, Roentgen pictures and to the most important - visible light. It&amp;rsquo;s all around us, thanks to it, you are able to read these words. But such a high number of these is invisible to us it might actually not exist. How do so many of these great technologies work, communicating (at the speed of light!</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 2</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/02/</guid><description>Mateusz Taking a look back to materials that made a lasting impression on me very few blog posts come to mind. I take this as a weakness of mine, but I ask for your attention regardless.
Physics is going to be finished in six months Thinking that you are something greater that you really are, is a trope that each homo sapiens embodies. Being an expert in a given field boosts your confidence to absurd levels but not equally in each specialization.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 1</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/01/</guid><description>Mateusz Efficiently Generating a Number in a Range You never thought about your random number generator. It just worked and you never noticed it to be off - except maybe for it&amp;rsquo;s slow performance. Meanwhile this posts proves that there are people that are thinking about this like it&amp;rsquo;s the basis of computing. Going over every little detail from correctness (!) and speed, and still one upping each-other on their implementation.</description></item></channel></rss>