<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on A link collection by Net-Enjoyers</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on A link collection by Net-Enjoyers</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Link collection: 3</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/third/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/third/</guid><description>Mateusz Wide-band WebSDR Electromagnetic radiation is a spectrum so incredibly attached to today&amp;rsquo;s humans it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine life without it. From radio, WiFi, Bluetooth, 4G/5G, TV, Roentgen pictures and to the most important - visible light. It&amp;rsquo;s all around us, thanks to it, you are able to read these words. But such a high number of these is invisible to us it might actually not exist. How do so many of these great technologies work, communicating (at the speed of light!</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 2</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/second/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/second/</guid><description>Mateusz Taking a look back to materials that made a lasting impression on me very few blog posts come to mind. I take this as a weakness of mine, but I ask for your attention regardless.
Physics is going to be finished in six months Thinking that you are something greater that you really are, is a trope that each homo sapiens embodies. Being an expert in a given field boosts your confidence to absurd levels but not equally in each specialization.</description></item><item><title>Link collection: 1</title><link>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/first/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://net-enjoyers.github.io/posts/first/</guid><description>Mateusz Efficiently Generating a Number in a Range You never thought about your random number generator. It just worked and you never noticed it to be off - except maybe for it&amp;rsquo;s slow performance. Meanwhile this posts proves that there are people that are thinking about this like it&amp;rsquo;s the basis of computing. Going over every little detail from correctness (!) and speed, and still one upping each-other on their implementation.</description></item></channel></rss>